unitec.ac.nz 2019-02-07

# Privacy Policy | Unitec

## Personal information and privacy

Thanks for visiting our website. We take the privacy of our website visitors seriously and aim to collect and maintain any personal information you provide us in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993 (NZ), with these terms and conditions and with Unitec’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.unitec.ac.nz/about-us/unitec-policies) and [Privacy Procedures (together referred to as “our Privacy Obligations”)](https://www.unitec.ac.nz/about-us/unitec-policies).

You have the right to access and correct personal information about you which has been collected by Unitec, in accordance with our Privacy Obligations.

## Using our site

While you may provide information to us, we also track the use of our website by site visitors. We don’t attempt to identify individuals as part of our regular business practice. However, the information recorded by our web server logs may be used by us or other government agencies in the event of an investigation.

When people visit our website we record your visit to our web server and by using tools such as Google Analytics. The information collected includes (but is not limited to):

  * The IP or internet address of your computer, server and browser including location
  * The date, time and length of your visit
  * The pages you view and documents you download
  * The type of browser and screen resolution you use
  * The website you were visiting before arriving at Unitec’s website

## Use of personal information

Unitec collects and holds personal information about students to comply with various statutes, including the Education Act, the Public Finance Act and the Crown Entities Act, and to enable Unitec to make decisions in relation to your tertiary study at Unitec. In particular, Unitec may use the personal information submitted by you via this website to process your application or enrolment, to assist with provision of services, to keep in touch with you if you are a graduate or to send you information about Unitec programmes.

Personal information collected from you during the enrolment process may be disclosed to academic and administration staff where relevant to their duties, and also where relevant to other agencies such as the Ministry of Education, Tertiary Education Commission, New Zealand Qualifications Authority, StudyLink, Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Trade, Career Services, iwi trusts and scholarship providers, Ministry of Immigration, Industry Training Organisations, Industry Licensing and Registration bodies, other tertiary institutions, previous secondary schools and providers of work experience for students in courses with a practical component.

Your name, date of birth and residency as entered on any enrolment form will also be included in the National Student Index, and will be used in an Authorised Information Matching programme with the New Zealand Birth Register. For more information please visit the [Ministry of Education website](http://www.education.govt.nz/).

In addition, when required by law, Unitec will release information to government agencies such as the New Zealand Police, Department of Justice, Inland Revenue and the Accident Compensation Corporation.

## Marketing and recruitment

Unitec collects, stores and uses contact details it is provided with, to engage with its customers and future students to recruit students.

If you submit your contact details and study interests to us, Unitec will:

  * Use the details you provide, including your email address, to send you information about programme offerings. The details will also be used to develop and assess the effectiveness of the marketing strategies and events, and to review associated enrolment trends over time.
  * Not disclose your information unless required or permitted by law.
  * Store your information securely in our systems and share securely with our partners. We take all reasonable steps to ensure the information provided remains secure.

You are responsible for ensuring the information you provide is correct and up to date. You can access or correct your information at any time by contacting [marketing@unitec.ac.nz](mailto:marketing@unitec.ac.nz).

If you wish to unsubscribe from specific types of communications, or from communication as a whole that is sent to you via our systems, use the unsubscribe link in any of the email communications you have received from Unitec or send your request to [marketing@unitec.ac.nz](http://marketing@unitec.ac.nz/). Please note that this will not unsubscribe you from all communications from Unitec where you have provided your information separately for other purposes or is a result of completing a transaction e.g. confirmation of application.

## Unitec advertising campaigns

Separate to direct subscription, Unitec also targets its advertising campaigns based on online behaviour (often referred to as targeted and online behavioural advertising).

After unsubscribing from our direct marketing activities, you may still receive other Unitec advertising based on online behaviour through the use of cookies or other technology. For more information, please refer to the Cookies and third-party services section.

Unitec also advertises through social media channels, including Facebook. If you make your personal information publicly available through social media platforms, Unitec may use it to provide targeted advertising campaigns and to find look-a-like audiences within social media.

You can update your social media profile settings and opt out of advertisements directly through the social media platforms. Instructions on how to do this can be found on their apps and websites.

## Cookies and third party services

A cookie, also known as a web cookie or browser cookie, is a small piece of data sent from a website and stored on a user's web browser. This site uses cookies for identifying visitors and for tracking the usage of our site so we can improve the performance and user experience for future visitors. We also use cookies to assist with our online chat service.

We may also use cookies for the purposes of advertising relevant offers or information to you once you have left our website. This involves Google and other vendors using Google’s Display Network (or similar), who may display ads to you on other websites based on your previous visits to Unitec’s website. If you would like to opt out of Google’s use of cookies for remarketing purposes, please visit [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

We use Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our website with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behaviour and their devices (in particular, a device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymised form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Neither Unitec or Hotjar will ever use this information to identify individual users. You can opt-out of Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site by following [this opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

With most web browsers you can change the settings to accept or reject cookies from websites you visit. Rejecting cookies may result in reduced website functionality.

We may also share customer information with third parties to perform services on our behalf including advertising and customer support.

### How to disable cookies

In your web browser you will have the option to disable/block cookies. Below are links to popular web browsers and their explanations on how to block cookies.

## European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

View our privacy policy information in relation to the GDPR.

If you have any questions or feedback about your web privacy please email [marketing@unitec.ac.nz](mailto:marketing@unitec.ac.nz).
